asphaltandrubber.com 2009-05-27

# Privacy Policy - Asphalt & Rubber

Asphalt & Rubber is founded on the principles of bringing motorcyclists together, and to provide them with a source for motorcycle related news and events. Asphalt & Rubber knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy very seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. By visiting the Asphalt & Rubber website, you are accepting the practices outlined in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy covers Asphalt & Rubber’s treatment of personal information that Asphalt & Rubber gathers when you are on the Asphalt & Rubber website and when you use Asphalt & Rubber services. This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Asphalt & Rubber does not own or control, or to individuals that Asphalt & Rubber does not employ or manage.

**Information Collected by  ** **Asphalt & Rubber**  
We only collect personal information that is relevant to the purpose of our website, which is to enable users to discover and share information with one another. This information allows us to provide you with a customized and efficient experience. We do not process this information in a way that is incompatible with this objective. We collect the following types of information from our Asphalt & Rubber users:

> Information You Provide to Us:  
>  We receive and store any information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of our special features.
> 
> Registration:   
>  In order for you to use Asphalt & Rubber commenting services, such as posting a comment to an article, you must complete a registration form. As part of this registration form, we require select personal information (including your name and e-mail address).
> 
> User Profile:   
>  To allow you to express yourself beyond just the information collected during registration, we enable you to provide additional information, such as a bio, favorite URLs, and instant messaging IDs. In addition, you may choose to include photos of yourself in your profile. As indicated below, in the section titled “Sharing Your Information”, you can control how your information is displayed and used.
> 
> Automatic Information:   
>  We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. Asphalt & Rubber and its authorized agents automatically receive and record certain “traffic data” on their server logs from your browser including your IP address, Asphalt & Rubber cookie information, and the page you requested. Asphalt & Rubber uses this traffic data to help diagnose problems with its servers, analyze trends and administer the website. Asphalt & Rubber may collect and, on any page, display the total counts that page has been viewed. This includes User Profile pages. Many companies offer programs that help you to visit websites anonymously. While Asphalt & Rubber will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience if we cannot recognize you, we want you to be aware that these programs are available.

**E-mail Communications**  
Asphalt & Rubber is very concerned about your privacy and we will never provide your email address to a third party without your explicit permission, as detailed in the “Sharing Your Information” section below. Asphalt & Rubber may send out e-mails with Asphalt & Rubber-related news, products, offers, surveys or promotions. You may also receive notification e-mails from Asphalt & Rubber, which inform you of actions (e.g. comments or recent news posts) that have been performed on the site. 

**Cookies**  
Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our website are visited and by how many people. Asphalt & Rubber cookies do not collect personal information, and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to tell us who you are or what your screen name or e-mail address is.

The “help” portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. We recommend that you leave the cookies activated because cookies allow you to use the majority of Asphalt & Rubber’s features hassle free.

Some of our business partners, like our advertisers, may use cookies on our website. We have no access to, or control over, these cookies.

**Sharing Your Information**  
Because Asphalt & Rubber enables people to discover and share information with one another, information about the people who use Asphalt & Rubber is an integral part of the Asphalt & Rubber experience. Rest assured that we neither rent nor sell your personal information to anyone and that we will share your personal information only as described below.

> Asphalt & Rubber Personnel:   
>  Asphalt & Rubber personnel and authorized consultants and/or contractors may have access to user information if necessary in the normal course of Asphalt & Rubber business.
> 
> Business Transfers:   
>  In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if Asphalt & Rubber, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred.
> 
> Protection of Asphalt & Rubber and Others: We may release personal information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with a law; to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other policies; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Asphalt & Rubber, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
> 
> Syndication:  
>  Asphalt & Rubber allows for the RSS syndication of all of its public content within the asphaltandrubber.com website.
> 
> With Your Consent:   
>  Except as noted above, we will contact you when your personal information is shared with third parties or used for a purpose incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected, and you will be able to opt out to prevent the sharing of this information.

**Keeping Information Secure**  
Your Asphalt & Rubber account information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. Protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer by logging off once you have finished using a shared computer. Only employees of Asphalt & Rubber, who need personal information to perform a specific job (for example, a customer service representative), are granted access to it. All of our employees are kept up to date on our privacy and security practices.

**Ways to Control Display and Use of Your Information**

As stated previously, you can always opt not to disclose information, but then you may be unable to use certain features on our website, such as posting new links.

You may request deletion of your Asphalt & Rubber account by contacting a [site administrator](mailto:editor@asphaltandrubber.com). Posts submitted, and comments made by a user will be deleted at the site administrator’s discretion.

**Children Under 18 Years of Age**  
You must be 13 years and older to register to use the Asphalt & Rubber website. As a result, Asphalt & Rubber does not specifically collect information about children. If we learn that Asphalt & Rubber has collected information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. We recommend that minors between the ages of 13 and 18 ask and receive their parents’ permission before using Asphalt & Rubber or sending information about themselves or anyone else over the Internet.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
Asphalt & Rubber may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, at its sole discretion. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by leaving a date of revision at the bottom of this document.

**Conditions of Use**  
If you decide to visit Asphalt & Rubber website, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of California state law.

**Effective Date of this Privacy Policy**  
This Privacy Policy is effective as of November 11, 2008.
